Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
We have an upper intermediate lesson for you today.
今天我们为大家准备了一节中高级课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
So today we're talking about something that everyone who's ever lived away from home has
所以今天我们要聊的是每个曾经离家生活过的人都
felt before.
感受过的事情。
Right.
没错。
And that's the word we're going to preview today.
这就是我们今天要预览的单词。
The word is homesick.
这个词是“homesick”（想家的）。
All right.
好的。
So let's take a look at that in today's language preview.
那么让我们在今天的语言预览中看看这个词。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So homesick.
所以，“homesick”。
If you feel homesick or you are homesick.
如果你感到想家或者你想家了。
Well, yeah, you could say I'm homesick right now.
嗯，是的，你可以说我现在想家了。
Or are you feeling homesick?
或者你感到想家吗？
So it's a word that means I miss my home.
所以这个词的意思是我想念我的家。
I miss my family.
我想念我的家人。
I'm far away or I haven't seen my family in a long time.
我离得很远，或者我很久没见到家人了。
And for some reason you just feel sad.
而且出于某种原因，你只是感到难过。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a feeling.
所以这是一种感觉。
You feel a little bit depressed.
你感到有点沮丧。
You feel sad because you're homesick.
你感到难过，因为你想家了。
Right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So this is what's happening today in our dialogue.
这就是我们今天对话中发生的事情。
So let's listen to it for the first time.
那么让我们第一次听一下。
Tom, how are you?
Tom，你好吗？
Hey, we missed you at the party last night.
嘿，我们昨晚在派对上没见到你。
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I didn't really feel like going out.
我真的不太想出去。
I guess I'm feeling a little homesick.
我想我有点想家了。
Come on.
别这样。
We've been through this already.
我们已经经历过这个了。
Look, I know the adjustment was hard when you first got here, but we agree that you're
听着，我知道你刚来的时候适应很困难，但我们说好了你
going to try and deal with it.
要努力应对的。
I was.
我一直在努力。
It's just that the holidays are coming up and I won't be able to go home because I can't
只是假期快到了，我回不了家，因为我
afford the airfare.
买不起机票。
I'm just longing for some of the comforts of home, like my mom's cooking and being around
我只是渴望一些家的舒适，比如我妈妈的饭菜和
my family.
和家人在一起。
Yeah, it can get pretty lonely over the holidays.
是啊，假期里确实会感到挺孤独的。
When I first got here, I'd get depressed and nostalgic for anything that reminded me of
我刚来的时候，也会感到沮丧和怀旧，任何让我想起
home.
家的东西都会这样。
I almost let it get to me, but then I started going out, keeping myself busy.
我差点被它击垮，但后来我开始出去走走，让自己忙起来。
And before I knew it, I was used to it.
不知不觉中，我就习惯了。
I see what you mean, but I'm still bummed out.
我明白你的意思，但我还是很难过。
Okay, how does this sound?
好吧，这样怎么样？
Let's get you suited up and hit the dance club tonight.
我们今晚打扮一下，去舞厅跳舞吧。
I hear that an awesome DJ is playing and there will be a lot of pretty single girls there.
我听说有个很棒的DJ在打碟，而且那里会有很多漂亮的单身女孩。
You know, I could really go for that.
你知道吗，我还真想去。
You don't mind being my wingman for tonight?
你不介意今晚当我的僚机吧？
Not at all.
完全不介意。
It'll be fun.
会很好玩的。
It will be like a boys' night out.
就像个男生之夜。
Well, kind of.
嗯，差不多吧。
Great.
太好了。
I must warn you, though.
不过我得警告你。
Whatever happens, don't let me go on a drinking binge.
不管发生什么，别让我喝得酩酊大醉。
Trust me, it's not a pretty picture.
相信我，那可不是什么好看的画面。
All righty, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So yeah, I guess he's very homesick.
所以，是的，我猜他非常想家。
Very homesick.
非常想家。
And his friend is really worried.
而且他的朋友真的很担心。
Yeah.
是啊。
But actually, I think this is common, right?
但实际上，我觉得这很常见，对吧？
To be homesick during the holidays, like Christmas, for example.
在假期里想家，比如圣诞节。
Oh, man, it's the worst during the holidays because you think of all the traditions and
哦，天哪，假期里最糟糕了，因为你会想起所有那些
all the things that you normally do at home and you're not doing them.
你通常在家做的传统和事情，而你却做不了。
So this is something we're going to talk more about a little bit later on.
所以这是我们稍后会多聊一点的话题。
But let's take a look at some of the language that was used in Language Takeaway.
但让我们先看看“语言要点”中使用的一些语言。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
This first one is key, right?
第一个是关键，对吧？
So when you move away from home or when you move to a new place, you have a period of
所以当你离开家或者搬到一个新地方时，你会有一段
adjustment.
适应期。
So adjustment is kind of finding the right balance or doing something so that you can
所以“adjustment”（适应）就是找到合适的平衡或做一些事情，以便你能
kind of feel comfortable.
感到舒适。
OK, so you have to adjust to your new life, life away from home.
好的，所以你必须适应你的新生活，远离家的生活。
Or your new environment.
或者你的新环境。
So many times people say, wow, moving to China must be a big adjustment.
所以很多时候人们会说，哇，搬到中国一定是个很大的适应过程。
So it means there's so many differences that it must take a long time to feel comfortable
所以这意味着有很多差异，需要很长时间才能再次感到舒适
again.
。
OK.
好的。
All right.
So that's adjustment.
这就是“adjustment”。
What else do we have?
我们还有什么？
Well, we've got this next phrase that's really important, I think, but often gets overlooked.
嗯，我们还有下一个短语，我觉得非常重要，但经常被忽视。
We say the comforts of home, right?
我们说“the comforts of home”（家的舒适），对吧？
Comforts of home.
家的舒适。
So comfort's pretty easy, right?
所以“comfort”很容易理解，对吧？
Feeling comfortable.
感到舒适。
So you have comfort.
所以你有舒适。
But the comforts of home are things that are different with every person.
但“家的舒适”是因人而异的。
But those are things that you have at your home or your childhood home or your parents'
但那些是你家里、童年家里或父母
home that make you feel good and feel happy.
家里让你感觉良好和快乐的东西。
So they're not only physical things or objects, right?
所以它们不仅仅是实物或物品，对吧？
They can be like your mom's cooking or maybe even just spending time with your family.
它们可以是像你妈妈的饭菜，或者只是和家人在一起的时间。
Right, or reading the newspaper with your dad or things that you're used to that you
没错，或者和爸爸一起看报纸，或者你习惯做但
don't have anymore.
不再拥有的东西。
And so those are the comforts of home.
所以那些就是家的舒适。
I could say, Marco, do you miss the comforts of home in Ecuador?
我可以说，Marco，你想念厄瓜多尔家里的舒适吗？
I mean, do you have anything that's really...
我是说，你有什么特别……
Of course, of course.
当然，当然。
I think one of the main things is actually not living in the city because I used to live
我觉得主要的一点其实是不住在城市里，因为我以前
in the valley a little bit further away and kind of almost countryside.
住在山谷里，稍微远一点，有点像乡村。
So that's one of the comforts of home that I miss.
所以那是我想念的家的舒适之一。
Oh, you're making me nostalgic and I've never even been.
哦，你让我感到怀旧了，我都没去过那里。
All right.
好的。
Well, this is our next word, actually.
嗯，这实际上是我们下一个词。
Right, nostalgic.
没错，“nostalgic”（怀旧的）。
Nostalgic.
怀旧的。
It's a feeling.
这是一种感觉。
I'm feeling nostalgic or he's just really nostalgic.
我感到怀旧，或者他只是非常怀旧。
And so to be nostalgic is to kind of think about a time before or think positively about
所以怀旧就是回想以前的日子，或者积极看待
something that you experienced before.
你以前经历过的事情。
So it's not usually a bad thing.
所以通常不是坏事。
It's never a bad thing.
从来不是坏事。
Nostalgia is a good, warm, fond memory of something.
怀旧是对某件事美好、温暖、珍贵的回忆。
Of something from your past.
对你过去某件事的回忆。
So you start thinking of something from your past that maybe brings nice, warm feelings,
所以你开始回想过去的一些事，那些可能带来美好、温暖感觉的事，
maybe a little bit sad because you miss those times, but it's usually thinking about the
也许有点伤感，因为你怀念那些时光，但通常是在回忆
past.
过去。
Right.
对。
So I have nostalgia for my childhood.
所以我怀念我的童年。
I loved, you know, summers in Chicago and it was hot and the kids would play in the
我喜欢，你知道，芝加哥的夏天，天气很热，孩子们在
sprinkler and I had my dog and you know, it's a happy feeling.
洒水器里玩耍，我养了我的狗，你知道，那是一种快乐的感觉。
Right.
对。
So nostalgia would be the noun and nostalgic would be the adjective.
所以 nostalgia 是名词，nostalgic 是形容词。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And our last word for today on Language Takeaway is bummed out.
今天“语言小贴士”的最后一个词是 bummed out。
Bummed out.
Bummed out。
I'm bummed out.
我很沮丧。
We've got another feeling here.
我们又有了另一种感觉。
So we're all full of feelings today.
所以我们今天充满了各种感觉。
Bummed out is a sad feeling.
Bummed out 是一种悲伤的感觉。
So to be bummed is kind of slang and it means to be sad.
所以 to be bummed 是一种俚语，意思是感到悲伤。
Okay.
好的。
Or disappointed.
或者失望。
Disappointed.
失望。
So you come into the office, Marco, and you look a little tired.
所以你走进办公室，Marco，看起来有点累。
I said, are you okay?
我说，你还好吗？
Are you bummed out about something?
你是不是因为什么事而沮丧？
I can say, yeah, I lost my wallet last night so I'm really bummed out.
我可以说，是啊，我昨晚丢了钱包，所以真的很沮丧。
Or something like that.
或者类似的情况。
So yeah, you feel bummed out when something bad or sad happens.
所以是的，当坏事或伤心事发生时，你会感到沮丧。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So let's move on now to a couple of different phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在我们进入“流利度提升”部分，看看几个不同的短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
All right.
好的。
This first one is something that you often say to old friends or family.
第一个是你经常对老朋友或家人说的话。
You know, when you're friends with someone, they go through periods of happiness and sadness.
你知道，当你和某人做朋友时，他们会经历快乐和悲伤的时期。
And so when someone's going through a down period again, you say, oh, we've been through
所以当某人再次经历低谷时，你会说，哦，我们之前已经
this already.
经历过这个了。
We've been through this already.
我们之前已经经历过这个了。
Or you know, when you're giving someone advice and they never take your advice, you say,
或者你知道，当你给别人建议，但他们从不采纳时，你会说，
listen, we've been through this already.
听着，我们之前已经经历过这个了。
You should know by now that I and then, you know, whatever the advice is.
你现在应该知道我会……然后，你知道，不管建议是什么。
So this has happened before or we have experienced this before or we already solved this problem
所以这表示这件事以前发生过，或者我们以前经历过，或者我们已经解决了这个问题
or situation.
或这种情况。
Right.
对。
You could imagine two bank robbers who are going over their plan for the 10th time and
你可以想象两个银行劫匪在第十次讨论他们的计划，
then one says to the other, hey, we've been through this already.
然后一个人对另一个人说，嘿，我们之前已经经历过这个了。
You should know the plan by now.
你现在应该知道计划了。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So we've been through this already.
所以我们之前已经经历过这个了。
They were talking about the adjustments and everything.
他们在讨论调整之类的事情。
And then what other phrase did they use?
然后他们用了什么别的短语？
Well, the next couple of phrases have to do with the friend's suggestions because she
嗯，接下来的几个短语和朋友的建议有关，因为她有很多主意
has a lot of ideas to cheer her friend up, the depressed one.
想让她的朋友（那个抑郁的人）开心起来。
And the first thing she says is, hey, let's hit the dance club.
她说的第一件事是，嘿，我们去舞厅吧。
Okay, let's hit the dance club or let's hit the dance floor tonight.
好的，我们去舞厅，或者今晚我们去舞池跳舞。
Right.
对。
So hit in this case doesn't mean like hit.
所以这里的 hit 不是打的意思。
It doesn't mean you're punching someone.
不是指你打人。
It means to go to or to do.
而是指去或做某事。
All right.
好的。
So we can say, let's go to the dance club tonight.
所以我们可以说，今晚我们去舞厅吧。
Let's hit the dance club.
我们去舞厅。
Exactly.
没错。
It doesn't have to be a dance club.
不一定非得是舞厅。
But let's hit that concert tonight.
但今晚我们去那个演唱会吧。
I really want to go there.
我真的很想去那里。
Okay.
好的。
So you can hit pretty much any place, right?
所以你可以去几乎任何地方，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And this is a very kind of spoken language.
这是一种非常口语化的表达。
So you wouldn't say this in your essays, but it's a good way to talk about plans with
所以你写文章时不会这么说，但和朋友讨论计划时
friends.
是个好方式。
All right.
好的。
And our next word actually is kind of interesting because it's very colloquial and it's a wingman.
我们的下一个词其实挺有意思的，因为它很口语化，就是 wingman。
I can be your wingman tonight.
我今晚可以当你的 wingman。
So wingman, you have to think about wing meaning side, not like a bird's wing.
所以 wingman，你得把 wing 想成“侧边”，不是鸟的翅膀。
So a wing means side and a wingman is a guy who will go with you to a bar or a club to
所以 wing 意思是侧边，wingman 是一个会陪你去酒吧或俱乐部，
kind of help you find a date or a girl or someone to talk to.
帮你找约会对象、女孩或聊天对象的人。
Okay.
好的。
So this person, this wingman usually keeps you company and helps you decide maybe what
所以这个人，这个 wingman 通常陪你，帮你决定
girl to talk to or maybe even introduces you to someone at a club or at a restaurant or
和哪个女孩聊天，甚至可能在俱乐部、餐厅、
bar or whatever.
酒吧之类的地方介绍你认识人。
And, you know, the key is that people don't like to go alone to bars, right?
而且，你知道，关键是人们不喜欢独自去酒吧，对吧？
Because you feel sad and then you look weird because you're all alone.
因为你会感到难过，而且一个人待着看起来很奇怪。
And the same is true for girls.
女孩也一样。
And so if a guy wants to go to a bar and he sees two girls, well, he has to have a friend
所以如果一个男人想去酒吧，看到两个女孩，那他得有个朋友
to talk to the other girl.
去和另一个女孩聊天。
So wingman also helps in that sense.
所以 wingman 在这方面也有帮助。
He helps balance things.
他帮助平衡局面。
All right.
好的。
So there's a whole science behind the wingman.
所以 wingman 背后有一整套学问。
I'm sure if you look it up on Wikipedia, you'll find 10 pages of information.
我敢肯定，如果你在维基百科上查，会找到十页的信息。
All right.
好的。
So since they are going out tonight, they said it could be boys night out.
既然他们今晚要出去，他们说了可能是“男生之夜”。
Okay.
好的。
And this is another phrase you hear all the time, especially among young people, boys
这是你经常听到的另一个短语，尤其是在年轻人中，“男生之夜”
night out and girls night out.
和“女生之夜”。
And so, you know, sometimes you spend a lot of time with your husband or your wife or
所以，你知道，有时你和丈夫、妻子、
your boyfriend or girlfriend and you just want to have some time with your friends.
男朋友或女朋友待久了，就想和朋友一起待会儿。
And so you call this girls night for me, girls night out.
所以对我来说，这叫“女生之夜”，女生之夜外出。
You just go out and you do girl things.
你只是出去做女生的事。
Guys night out, you do other things.
男生之夜外出，你做别的事。
And so in this case, it's girls only or guys only.
所以在这种情况下，只有女生或只有男生。
Boys night out is only guys.
“男生之夜”只有男生。
Exactly.
没错。
And that's why this is funny because it's the girl who says, hey, let's have boys night
这就是为什么这很有趣，因为是一个女孩说，嘿，我们来个
out.
男生之夜吧。
And she's not really a boy.
而她并不是男生。
All right.
好的。
Great.
太好了。
And well, he agreed to go out and everything, but he warned her about him going on a drinking
嗯，他同意出去了，但他警告她关于他可能会
binge.
酗酒。
Okay.
好的。
Now, this is important.
现在，这很重要。
A lot of people who are depressed or sad when they drink, they drink a lot.
很多抑郁或悲伤的人喝酒时会喝很多。
And so binge means to do something in excess, to do it too much.
所以 binge 意思是过度做某事，做得太多。
Okay.
好的。
So a drinking binge would be drinking alcohol in excess, too much.
所以 drinking binge 就是过度饮酒，喝得太多。
Too much.
太多了。
So getting drunk right away.
所以很快就喝醉了。
And it's not healthy and we do not condone it.
这不健康，我们也不提倡。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
很好。
So we're going to stop with the phrases in this dialogue today.
所以我们今天对话中的短语就到这里。
I think we should listen to it one more time and we'll be right back.
我觉得我们应该再听一遍，然后马上回来。
Tom, how are you?
汤姆，你好吗？
Hey, we missed you at the party last night.
嘿，我们昨晚在派对上没见到你。
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I didn't really feel like going out.
我真的不太想出门。
I guess I'm feeling a little homesick.
我想我有点想家了。
Come on.
别这样。
We've been through this already.
我们之前已经经历过这个了。
Look, I know the adjustment was hard when you first got here.
听着，我知道你刚来的时候适应起来很难。
But we agree that you're going to try and deal with it.
但我们说好你会努力应对的。
I was.
我确实在努力。
It's just that the holidays are coming up and I won't be able to go home because I can't
只是假期快到了，我回不了家，因为我付不起
afford the airfare.
机票钱。
I'm just longing for some of the comforts of home, like my mom's cooking and being around
我只是渴望一些家里的舒适，比如妈妈做的菜和
my family.
家人在一起。
Yeah, it can get pretty lonely over the holidays.
是啊，假期里确实会感到挺孤独的。
When I first got here, I'd get depressed and nostalgic for anything that reminded me of
我刚来的时候，会感到沮丧和怀旧，任何让我想起
home.
家的东西都会触动我。
I almost let it get to me, but then I started going out, keeping myself busy.
我差点被它击垮，但后来我开始出门，让自己忙起来。
And before I knew it, I was used to it.
不知不觉中，我就习惯了。
I see what you mean.
我明白你的意思。
But I'm still bummed out.
但我还是很难过。
Okay, how does this sound?
好吧，这样怎么样？
Let's get you suited up and hit the dance club tonight.
今晚我们给你打扮好，去舞厅跳舞。
I hear that an awesome DJ is playing and there will be a lot of pretty single girls there.
我听说有个超棒的DJ在表演，而且会有很多漂亮的单身女孩。
You know, I could really go for that.
你知道吗，我还真想去。
You don't mind being my wingman for tonight?
你不介意今晚当我的僚机吧？
Not at all.
完全不介意。
It'll be fun.
会很好玩的。
It will be like a boys' night out.
就像男生之夜一样。
Well, kind of.
嗯，差不多吧。
Great.
太好了。
I must warn you, though, whatever happens, don't let me go on a drinking binge.
不过我得警告你，不管发生什么，别让我喝得酩酊大醉。
Trust me, it's not a pretty picture.
相信我，那场面可不好看。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So speaking of homesick and holidays, do you actually get very depressed or homesick during
说到想家和假期，你在圣诞节期间真的会感到非常沮丧或想家吗？
Christmas?
圣诞节？
I do.
我会的。
Well, my family has a lot of Christmas traditions that are just really kind of wonderful and
嗯，我家有很多圣诞传统，真的特别美好，
we do them every single year.
而且我们每年都会做。
And so the first time I spent Christmas away, I was living in Italy and it was kind of similar.
所以第一次离开家过圣诞节时，我住在意大利，感觉还挺相似的。
But then the second time was when I was living in China.
但第二次是我住在中国的时候。
And China was just not the same.
而中国就完全不一样了。
No oven, so no Christmas cookies.
没有烤箱，所以没有圣诞饼干。
And no granny who, you know, pours vodka and eats meatballs.
也没有奶奶，你知道的，倒伏特加、吃肉丸。
And like my mom not running around the kitchen.
也没有妈妈在厨房里忙来忙去。
You feel lonely and then all of a sudden you get a phone call.
你会感到孤独，然后突然接到一个电话。
And it's the entire family and they're all together eating, having an amazing Christmas
是全家打来的，他们聚在一起吃饭，过着一个美妙的圣诞节，
and they think it's going to help you feel less homesick, but it makes you feel more
他们以为这样能让你不那么想家，但实际上让你更
homesick.
想家了。
So you definitely have nostalgia for those days during the holidays.
所以你在假期里肯定会怀念那些日子。
But what about you?
那你呢？
I rarely get homesick, but yeah, sometimes during Christmas or New Year's, New Year's
我很少想家，但嗯，有时候在圣诞节或新年期间，新年
we usually have more unique traditions in Ecuador.
在厄瓜多尔我们通常有更独特的传统。
So it's very fun.
所以很有趣。
The family gets together, we dance, we eat.
家人聚在一起，我们跳舞、吃饭。
So but yeah, I've been away from home so long that I rarely get homesick anymore.
但嗯，我离家太久了，所以很少再想家了。
But it's great to go back and spend time with the family.
但回去和家人团聚还是很棒的。
So after my visit to Ecuador, then I might get homesick for a little while, but then
所以在我回厄瓜多尔之后，我可能会短暂地想家，但然后
it goes away.
这种感觉就消失了。
Yeah.
嗯。
Well, you guys should tell us.
好了，你们应该告诉我们。
Do you ever feel homesick?
你们会想家吗？
And if you do, what do you feel homesick about?
如果会，你们想家时想念什么？
What do you miss?
你们想念什么？
Maybe mom's cooking, maybe family, maybe the comforts of home.
也许是妈妈的饭菜，也许是家人，也许是家里的舒适。
Yeah, so we're curious to hear your answers.
嗯，我们很想知道你们的答案。
We have a website, EnglishPod.com.
我们有一个网站，EnglishPod.com。
You can of course also leave us questions.
你们当然也可以给我们留言提问。
We're happy to answer those.
我们很乐意回答。
And until next time, everyone.
下次再见，各位。
Bye bye.
拜拜。